When we get started with Amazon,
we have to talk about AWS regions.
AWS has regions all around the world,
so you may have heard something like this
called us-east-1, or if you take, for example,
the Sydney region is called ap-southeast-2.
AWS has just a bunch of regions around the world,
and region is what you think it is.
It is, basically, somewhere in the world.
Each region will have Availability Zone.
Now, Availability Zone, we know and recognize them
because they end up with a letter,
so example, us-east-1a or us-east-1b, and so on.
The letters are A, B, C, D, E, and F,
can go up to six AZs so far.
So AZ is another word for Availability Zone,
and they're basically representing
physical data centers in a region,
so think like a huge data center somewhere in the world.
All these Availability Zones, they're separate
from one another because they're
want to be separate from disasters,
so this is why we have multiple AZ in one region.
Each AWS region is basically built around
a minimum of three data center or Availability Zones,
and that's the basis of how Amazon works.
Each AWS Console now are region scoped, except IAM and S3.
Basically, when we go into the AWS UI,
as you'll see in a second, you will be scoped to a region,
and what that means is that when you
do changes or when you perform actions,
you will perform this action in a specific region.
Now the AZ themselves are a subset of the region,
but they're not shown in the console.
So if we go to the console right here,
we can see that right now, I am in the Paris region,
but if I click on the top right, I can see a dropdown
of all the regions for AWS that exist.
If I take a service, such as, for example, EC2,
we can see that when the EC2 pages load,
we can see that the region is still Paris, okay?
Whereas, if I go back to the console
and type in the center bar, I type IAM and click on IAM,
now I can see that IAM is a global service,
and in the top right it says global,
and then it says IAM does not require region selection.
So there's a few services that don't require a region,
there's a few services that do require a region.
The best to work with when you start with Amazon
is to work in the region closest to you.
You can go to the Global Cloud Infrastructure
About AWS page, just Google Global Cloud Infrastructure,
and it will show you exactly on the map
where are all these regions and
how many AZs they have within them.
So basically we have the EU West region right here,
we have the US East, US West right here,
so there's a bunch of regions that you can see,
and within each region, they tell you
the number of AZs they have.
Now, for this tutorial, I want you to take a region
with at least three AZ, for this whole course,
because it really is the basis to me of how AWS works,
and that's pretty much the standard everywhere, so when you
do this tutorial, choose a region that is close to you.
If you live in Brazil, take a region in South America.
If you live near China, take the region
that is closest to you; if you live in the US,
do not choose Australia or Europe as your region.
That's just the basics, region and AZ,
and now we're ready to get started with Amazon Cloud.