So let's talk about routing policy
and the first one is going to be Simple Routing Policy.
And it's used to map a domain to a URL.
So simple, right?
We have a web browser and Route 53
and we just say, okay, we wanna know where
is foo.example.com?
Route 53 will reply it is in A record
and the IP is 11.22.33.44.
Excellent!
So we'll just use it basically
when we need to redirect to a single resource.
It's very easy, simple routing, right?
And the thing is with simple routing,
you can not attach health checks.
So we have not seen health checks just yet.
We'll see them in a few lectures.
But, health checks can not be attached
to simple routing policy.
So it's that easy, very simple.
That's why it's named simple.
In simple though
you can return multiple values to a client
in which case the client sees all the values
and the client will choose a value at random to use.
So let's have a look at how this works in practice.
So in this example, I'm going to create a Record Sets
and I'm going to call it simple.
That's to stephanetheteacher.com.
It's going to be an A record
and the TTL is going to be set to 60 seconds only,
and the value is going to be my URL in,
for example us-west-1.
So I'll just choose this one.
And I'll paste it in.
Click on create and we're done.
Okay, so this was a simple record
and we have a load TTL of 60 seconds to one minute.
And so as you can expect,
if I go to simple.stephanetheteacher.com,
what we see is a Hello World
directly coming from us-east-1a.
If I use Dig to basically query for this URL,
what do we learn?
Well, we'll learn that,
and I don't need to use http
otherwise things will not work.
So let's try again.
We'll learn that, yes, we have 59 seconds of TTL left
and the IP result is 3.86.116.186.
Okay, that's as simple as simple gets.
But, we can make this a little bit more complicated.
Basically, by going and adding another IP.
So, for example here, instead of just having
one IP address, I can have multiple IP addresses.
So I'll just chose another one
from my instance in Ireland.
I'll select this IP address.
And as we can see here,
you can basically enter multiple IP addresses
on separate lines.
So here we have two IP addresses
and what this means is that when the web browser
will query for simple.stephanetheteacher.com
it will receive two addresses back.
And then my browser will choose
to which IP to go.
Could be very helpful,
basically if you want the web browser
to start doing some load balancing,
it's called client side load balancing.
So if I use Dig and now query for this little domain,
as we can see now the answer I'm getting back
is that I have two answers.
I have two A records
and two different IP addresses available to me.
Similarly if I go and open up
the back my simple.stephanetheteacher.com URL,
with a bit of luck
I've been transferred to eu-west-1c.
And so if I refresh this page
for 60 seconds it's for sure always
going to go to eu-west-1c,
but after 60 seconds my web browser
will make another DNS request
and there's a chance I will fall back
to this value again.
So it's something very important to see.
It's simple, but as we go along in this section,
we'll see more complicated policies
and it's always nice to start
with something a little bit simple.
So have a play.
Play with the TTL.
Play with the different IPs.
Play with Dig or nslookup
and I will see you in the next lecture.