Okay, hello, cloggers.
And thank you so much for taking this course.
My colleague Mark Richman and I will be teaching you everything you need to know to pass the Certified
Solutions Architect Associate Exam.
My name is Ryan Kronenburg.
I'm an A.W. community here and Alexa Champion, and I'm the co-founder of a Cloud Guru.
Over the last five years, a cloggers tolt cloud computing took over two million people suer and really,
really good hands.
In this course, we're going to assume that you have no prior A.W. s knowledge.
I didn't start out in tech myself.
I used to be an immigration lawyer.
And in 2010, I decided I wanted to retrain and I went to night school and I learnt cloud computing.
So I've done the exact same journey as you.
This course is really hands on.
It's not death by PowerPoint.
And the best way to learn a W.S. is to get your hands dirty in this course.
We're going to start by looking at a ten thousand foot overview of A.W. s.
They're going to move on to Identity Access Management in S3, but they're going to look at E.S. databases
advanced.
I am 53 VPC.
Hey, hey.
Architecture applications, security.
And then finally move on to Serverless and you're even going to learn how to build your very own Alexis
skill.
Like I said, this course is very hands on and you learn everything.
You need to know how to pass your exam as well as having lots of fun.
So let's go ahead and get started.